Alexandre Stanislawski

Software designer

http://bobylito.me | https://github.com/bobylito

I am a software engineer who is specialized in the use of web technologies with eight years of professional experience on a variety of projects and roles. I am very interested by new subjects and I am always looking for new ways to challenge myself on various subjects, such as visual effects or machine learning. I have a personal commitment to bringing developers, hackers and technology enthusiasts together in communities like DemoJS and Paris.js; a commitment that often leads me to organize and participate in similar events and groups in my work environment. Last but not least, I believe in lifelong learning and this is why I regularly take courses on a number of subjects for professional, as well as personal improvement.

Experience

Zengularity (2011-2014)

PELLUCID ANALYTICS (SINCE SEPTEMBER 2012)

US startup building SAAS tools for finance analysts

Technologies: Javascript, Stylus, Scala, Datomic, AWS, Play Framework 2

Role: Senior software designer / framework architect

Key missions:

Design and development of a data visualization framework using Scala

Development of a mobile and desktop application for financial analysts

Design and development of a mobile oriented application framework that extensively uses promises for structuring the flow of the application

Development of the early version of the data extraction back end

FOYER ASSURANCES (FROM JANUARY 2012 UNTIL AUGUST 2012)

Private insurance based in Luxembourg.

Technologies: Java, Javascript, ¡Query, Less.css, Play Framework

Roles: Consultant, software designer

Key missions:

Development of the javascript UI Framework

Development of an internal application

Web development best practices tutor

LCL (FROM JANUARY 2011 UNTIL DECEMBER 2011)

Major french bank

Technologies: Javascript, java, JEE

Role: Consultant Key missions:

Development of the UI framework used for building client applications

Coaching on development best practices

Tutoring on javascript and web best practices

Accenture Technology Solutions (2006 - 2010)

CLIENTS

French ministry for the economy and finance, Vente-privée.com, Intériale, EDF, GDF, Caisse des dépots et consignations

MAIN ROLES

Software designer, developper, release manager, business analyst

MAIN TECHNOLOGIES INVOLVED

Java, JEE Portals and portlets, Javascript, jQuery

Communities and events

DEMOJS (ONCE A YEAR SINCE 2011)

The parisian web demoparty.

Paris. Js (EACH MONTH SINCE 2011)

Javascript community.

Skills

Programming languages: Javascript, Scala, Java Web standards: HTML, CSS, Canvas, SVG, WebGL

Frontend frameworks: React, Backbone

Backend frameworks: Play Framework 1 and 2

Mobile device: Phonegap Source control: Git, SVN, CVS

Education

Double MSc in:

Mathematic and computer science engineering (Maitrise IUP Génie Mathématique et informatique) - Paris 7, Denis Diderot

Computer science (Maitrise d'informatique) - Paris 7, Denis Diderot

Completed online courses:

Gamification, coursera, 2012

Introduction to functionnal programming in scala, coursera, 2012 (as well as in 2013 as a mentor for my company)

Introduction to AI, ai-class, 2011 Machine learning, mI-class, 2011